My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
Can I flush out the truth?
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
Secret remains for you
Don't expose these false colors and futures
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 翼叔   校对:西西   后期:时末
The victim is Daisuke Shioyama,
twenty-seven years old.
被害者は塩山大輔 ２７歳
He worked at the Hachioji Drone factory.
八王子ドローン工場　勤務
His body was found at precisely 4 AM.
午前４時ちょうどに死体が発見された
They said he was dismembered
by a Drone he was testing.
テスト中のドローンによって体をバラバラにされたらしい
Do you think... it was an accident?
事故…　でしょうか
I heard that this is already the third
casualty in the past year at this factory.
問題の工場で死傷者が出るのはこの１年間ですでに３人目だそうだ
It's clearly unusual.
明らかに異常だ
The body was found in the Drones'
behavior inspection section,
現場はドローンの挙動検査セクション
the only manned area in the
completely automated production line.
完全自動化された生産ラインの中で 唯一の有人区画だ
About fifty debuggers
are there around the clock.
ここにはおよそ５０人余りのデバッガが常駐している
Is that a live-in job?
泊まり込みなんですか
If over 1000 Drones...
たったそれだけの人数で
...need to be evaluated and verified
by that few people every month,
毎月１０００台以上のドローンを評価検証するとなれば
they have no choice
but to work around the clock.
フルタイムシフトを組むしかない
If you install a program that induces
a malfunction in a Drone before it's tested,
検査前のドローンに誤作動を誘発するプログラムを仕込めば
there's a good chance you
can make it look like an accident.
事故を装った犯行はじゅうぶんに可能だ
Which means...
ということは…
It's possible that this is a murder case.
殺人の可能性もある
But if there are only fifty people,
if we check everyone's Crime Coefficient...
でも たった５０人しかいない環境なら
全員の犯罪係数をチェックすれば…
Well, it's not that simple.
事はそう簡単な話じゃなくてな
#03: Rearing Conventions
宜野座監視官
Inspector Ginoza...
What is it?
何だ
I feel like I'll be able to get
along well with the Enforcers.
私　執行官のみんなとうまくやっていけそうな気がします
Do you mean get along
with them as colleagues?
それは同僚としてやっていけそうという意味か
Or do you mean as their handler?
それとも調教師としてやっていけそうという意味か
They say that fools
learn from their experiences,
愚か者は経験に学び
while the wise learn from history.
賢者は歴史に学ぶという
I hope you're not a fool.
君が愚か者でないことを祈ろう
Welcome, detectives.
ようこそ刑事さん
I'd like to see where it happened.
現場を見せていただきます
Of course. I'll show you the way.
もちろん 案内しましょう
We do a safety check, as well as a
test run, here after the Drones are built.
ここでは組み上がったドローンの試運転を兼ねた
安全点検を行っています
We depend on machines for
all the other processes,
他の工程は全て機械任せですが
but the final check still needs to be
done by humans, just as it's always been.
最終チェックだけは今も昔も人間の手でやるしかない
As you can see, it's dangerous work.
見てのとおり危険な業務です
Isn't it quite tough on debuggers?
デバッガの方々にとってもかなりの負担なのでは？
Yes, it is.
そうですね
In fact, there aren't many
ways to deal with stress here,
実際ここは外と違ってストレスケアの手段が乏しい
unlike in the outside world.
Since you can't connect to the net,
there aren't many diversions, so...
ネットに接続できないので娯楽の手段も限られていますし
Is this place offline?
オフラインなんですか？ここ
We aren't wired for it,
回線そのものが設置されていませんし
and this building itself
is an anechoic chamber.
この建物自体が電波暗室になっています
So there's no way to access outside
communications networks here.
なので外部の通信網にアクセスする手段は一切ありません
This is the most efficient
security system against hacking.
ハッキング対策としては最も効率の高い保安体制です
How horrifying...
A totally isolated area, huh?
ぞっとするねえ 陸の孤島かよ
The body has already been taken away
by a Drone during the initial response.
死体はすでに初動でドローンが処理した後でして
I was told that this is the record of that.
こちらが記録だそうです
So it was like his body was dissected
by a Drone while he was still alive...
死体はドローンに生きたまま解剖された状態か
Nasty...
すっげえ
Did the victim, Mr. Shioyama,
have anyone with a grudge against him?
被害者塩山さん
誰かに恨みを買うようなことは？
No, he didn't.
He was an excellent worker.
ありませんよ 優秀なスタッフでした
特にサイコパスにも問題なし
His Psycho-Pass showed no
indication of problems.
It must have been an accident.
やはり事故ですよ
But this is the third incident.
Don't you think it's happening too often?
しかしこれで３人目となると
さすがに多過ぎやしませんかね
As I told you earlier, this is
a dangerous work environment.
先ほども申し上げたとおり危険の多い現場なのです
If you have criticisms of
our management, we're all ears,
管理体制についての批判であれば承りますが
but please air those concerns
through the appropriate channels.
そちらはしかるべき筋を通してお願いしたいですね
暴走したドローンの分解調査は
What about the inspection of
the Drone that went out of control?
I'm having it sent to headquarters.
本部に搬送を手配した
We'll just have to wait for
Karanomori to complete her analysis,
あとは唐之杜の分析待ちだが
but I was told that its memory,
including the backup, is gone.
メモリーが予備を含めて吹っ飛んでるらしい
We probably shouldn't expect much.
あまり期待しない方がいいだろう
For now, head back to the car
and forward this to headquarters.
いったん車に戻って
こいつを本部に転送してくれ
I need to talk to Chief Goda more.
俺は郷田主任ともう少し話がある
Okay.
分かりました
These are the Psycho-Passes
for all the staff within this facility.
こちらが施設内の全職員のサイコパスになります
This record contains the
results of our detailed periodic checks
定期診断の詳細値と常設スキャナーによる色相判定の記録です
along with the Hue Assessments
by the scanners installed in the building.
Thank you.
お預かりします
You'll see for yourself when you check it,
確認していただければ分かることですが
but no staff members continuously
exceeded the regulation value.
継続的に規定値を逸脱している職員は一人もいません
Even if you suspect murder,
there's no suspect to be found.
殺人を疑うにしても
まず容疑者がいませんよ
We won't know that until we analyze
this data using the Sibyl System.
それはこちらのデータを
シビュラシステムで分析してみるまで分かりません
That will take some time.
相応の時間がかかります
But there's an easier way to check.
だがより簡単に調べる方法もある
Oh? Like?
というと？
We can use our Dominators.
ドミネーターです
Please have all the staff come
outside the anechoic chamber
一度全ての職員を電波暗室の外に出し
and let us check them using our devices.
こちらの機材でチェックさせてください
But that'll disrupt our operations.
しかし　それではこちらの業務に支障を来す
This involves people's lives.
事は人命に関わる問題ですよ
If you submit evidence that
Shioyama's case is a murder case,
塩山君の一件が殺人事件であるという証拠を提出してくだされば
we will certainly cooperate with you.
もちろん当方も協力します
But as things stand, we have no choice
but to consider this an accident.
ですが現状あれは事故と判断するしかない
If you want to investigate our staff
even to the point of disrupting production,
こちらの業務を阻害してまで職員の取り調べを行うのであれば
please file a request with
the Ministry of Economy first.
まずは経済省を通して業務計画の変更手続きをお願いします
I bet Nobuchika is trying to put
some pressure on that chief by now.
今ごろ伸元はここの主任相手に腹芸の真っ最中だろうさ
What a pain...
難儀なこった
What do you mean?
どういうことですか
You saw the documents, too, right?
朱ちゃんも資料見たっしょ
This is a government facility under
the jurisdiction of the Ministry of Economy.
ここってば経済省管轄の官営なんよ
Government offices try to protect
the profit within their territories.
お役所は縄張りの利益を守ろうとするからね
So they don't want anyone meddling
and causing a drop in productivity.
余計なちょっかい出されて工場の生産効率を落としたくはないよね
When someone's life was lost?
人の命が失われたのに？
That's exactly why they want to settle
it as an accident as soon as possible.
だからこそ向こうは一刻も早く事故死で決着をつけたいんだ
But their scanner hasn't actually
detected anyone dangerous, right?
でも実際
ここのスキャナーは危険人物を検知してないんですよね
Well, who knows...
さて　どうだかな
At best, what the installed
scanners can measure is
据え置きのスキャナーで計測できるのは
a person's stress patterns
by performing a Hue Assessment.
せいぜいが色相判定によるストレス傾向ぐらいなもんだ
If you are to compute a person's
mental state based on the cymatic scan data
サイマティックスキャンのデータを基に精神構造を割り出し
and check their job aptitude and Crime Coefficient,
職業適性やら犯罪係数まで診断するとなれば
it'll require an analysis by the Sibyl System.
シビュラシステムによる解析が必要になる
There's always a waiting
line for Sibyl's analysis.
そして俺たちのドミネーターは
But no matter what tasks are waiting,
シビュラが常時抱えている演算待ちのタスク全てに優先して
our Dominators can cut into
that line and request an analysis.
割り込み処理を要請できる
That's why they can lay bare
a person's mind with no time lag
だから銃口を向けた途端
as soon as you point the gun at them.
タイムラグなしで相手の心を丸裸にできるのさ
But...
ところが…
Hold it in your hand.
抜いてみな
User authentication,
Inspector Akane Tsunemori.
「ユーザー認証　常守朱監視官」
Dominator usage approval confirmed.
「使用許諾確認」
Communication error.
System link cannot be established.
「通信エラー システムとのリンクを構築できません」
Since all kinds of radio waves are blocked,
あらゆる電波が遮断されてる以上
we can't receive support from
the Sibyl System within this facility.
この施設の中ではシビュラシステムの支援が受けられない
When that's the case,
Dominators are basically just scrap iron.
そうなるとドミネーターは鉄くずも同然だ
It's nothing but a glorified paperweight.
文鎮の代わりにしかならん
I wonder what the chances are...
本当のところ　どうなんでしょう？
You mean the possibility
that the death was an accident?
事故死の可能性ってか？
Ha! It was hard not to laugh.
笑わないようにするのが大変だった
No kidding.
ですよね
If your intuition didn't tell you when
you saw that place, you aren't a detective.
あの現場見て直感できなきゃデカじゃねえよ
I'm sure all the Enforcers had a gut feeling.
執行官なら全員ぴんときたはずだ
That was a murder. A murder.
殺しだよ 殺し
I wonder what the motive was.
動機は何でしょうね
Based on the victim's condition,
my intuition tells me that...
ホトケのありさまから直感で言わせてもらえば
it was a grudge.
怨恨だな
At any rate, this is such an
unpleasant workplace.
それにしても嫌な職場だよな
To think that they're stuck in an
offline environment in this day and age...
きょうびネットに接続できない環境で缶詰めとはね
But the Psycho-Pass Hues
for the workers here are rather stable.
でも　ここの人たちのサイコパス色相わりと安定してるよ
No matter where you are, people find
a way to entertain themselves.
どんな場所でも気晴らしの方法は…
How's it going?
Did you find anything suspicious?
いかがです？
何か不審な点は見つかりましたか？
No. The data you gave us
showed nothing out of the ordinary.
いえ 頂いたデータからは特に
Hey, yellow-green.
よお　黄緑野郎
Are you going to have lunch in
your fancy private room again today?
今日もまた優雅に個室でランチかい？
What is that? That's terrible!
何ですか？あれは ひどい
Oh, that. It's okay to leave them be.
あれはいいんです 放っておいて
Huh?
は？
These things happen often.
よくあることなんですよ
Since this is an environment
with few diversions,
なにぶん娯楽の少ない環境ですからね
we need a person to be in that position.
１人ああいう立場の人間が必要なんですよ
But he is...
でもあの人は…
If his Psycho-Pass
gets so clouded that it's a problem,
問題になるほどサイコパスが濁れば即座に配置換えを行います
we'll assign him somewhere else right away.
As I told you, we take great care to
manage our staff's psychological state.
言ったでしょう？
メンタル管理にはじゅうぶん配慮していると
He is helpful in his own way.
彼は彼で役に立っている
Sibyl might've recommended
this workplace to him
ああいう役回りがふさわしいからこそ
because he's suited for that kind of role.
シビュラにこの職場を勧められたんじゃないですかね
And someone like you,
who can laugh and overlook it,
それを笑って見過ごせるあんたも
is suited to run this place.
ここの責任者がお似合いってわけだ
What a blessing the Sibyl System is, huh?
シビュラシステムさまさまだな
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
すっ　すみません…
Th-Thank you.
If what that chief guy said is true,
あの主任の言ってたとおりだと
there's always one person whose
Hue Check gets worse over time.
常に一人だけ色相チェックが悪化しているやつがいて
And this person is later transferred
to somewhere else without exception.
そいつは例外なく後に転属処分を受けているよな
However, no one has been
reassigned for the past year.
ところがここ１年配置換えはない
The deaths started happening a year ago, right?
死亡事件が起こるようになったのも１年前からですよね
For the past year, the same
person has been the target of bullying.
この１年間ずっと同じ職員がいじめの対象になってるんだ
The data clearly indicates it.
データで一目瞭然だな
Other people's Psycho-Passes
show clear colors,
他の連中はクリアカラーなのに
but there's one person whose
Psycho-Pass is clouded.
サイコパスを濁らせてるやつが一人だけ
Ah! Yuji Kanehara. His Hue
Assessment shows yellow-green.
あっ！金原祐治 色相判定　イエローグリーン
I see, that's why he was called "yellow-green."
なるほど それで黄緑野郎か
Seems like the Hue Assessment
results are open to everyone here.
ここでは色相判定の結果が全員に公開されるらしいな
This is crazy.
どうかしてる
But this guy's latest measurement
shows an improved Hue.
でもこいつ最新の計測値だと色相が好転してるよ
Rather, his Hue was the cloudiest...
むしろ濁りがピークだったのは塩山の死の前日か
...on the day before Shioyama died.
Can't be... That doesn't make sense.
そんな…おかしいですよ
A person's Psycho-Pass
would improve after killing someone?
人を殺しておいてサイコパスがむしろ好転するなんて…
Everyone else besides Kanehara
is relieving their stress by hurting him.
金原以外の職員は金原を痛めつけることでストレスを解消してるんだ
So there's no mystery there.
何も不思議なことじゃない
Back in the days when
we didn't have cymatic scans,
サイマティックスキャンなんてなかった時代には
something like this wasn't really uncommon.
別段珍しい話じゃなかったんだぜ こういうの
Get real!
ふざけるな！
Is this that "detective's intuition"
you always talk about again?
またお得意の刑事の勘か？
You're just deluding yourself!
そいつはただの妄想だ
It proves that latent criminals
like you are the trash of society!
貴様のような潜在犯が
ただの社会のくずにすぎないという証拠だ
We can't act on some speculation
based on circumstantial evidence.
状況証拠に基づいた臆測で行動はできない
Our job is...
俺たちの任務はシビュラの判定した犯罪係数を基に
...to maintain an orderly society based
on the Crime Coefficient judged by Sibyl.
社会の秩序を維持することだ
Maintain the kind of order
where three people die within one year?
１年に３人も死人が出るような秩序を…　か？
Gino, let me do it.
ギノ 俺にやらせろ
As to whether Kanehara is the one or not...
金原がクロどうなのか すぐにでも確証をつかんで…
I'll quickly obtain conclusive evidence and...
黙れ！
Enough already!
Mr. Ginoza, may I speak to you?
宜野座さん　ちょっと…
I agree with them.
私 みんなに賛成です
If the alternative is for us to overlook a crime,
ここで犯罪を見過ごすぐらいなら
I'd rather want to try Mr. Kogami's plan.
狡噛さんの計画を試してみたい
Are you being serious?
君は…正気で言ってるのか？
宜野座さんこそ　どうかしてます！
You're the one who's acting strange here!
Did something happen between you and Mr. Masaoka?
征陸さんと何かあったんですか？
I... I can do a better job
working with the Enforcers!
わ…私は…執行官とももっとうまくやれます！
I see. So you're going
to take the fool's path.
なるほど　君は愚か者の道を進もうというわけか
You may be new,
but you're still an Inspector.
君も監視官の端くれだ
If you think you can control the hunting
dogs well, then you're welcome to try.
猟犬どもをうまく手なずけられると思うなら
やってみろ
Mr. Ginoza...
宜野座さん…
You're a fool, so like a fool,
you should try learning through experience.
愚か者は愚か者らしく
何もかも経験で学んでみるがいい
That's the fastest route to
understanding things.
それが理解への早道だ
宜野座さんって　征陸さんと何かあったんですか？
Did something happen between
Mr. Ginoza and Mr. Masaoka?
Wait, Akane, don't tell me you
seriously asked Gino that to his face?!
朱ちゃん それ ギノさんの前で持ち出しちゃった？
You said something you shouldn't have.
地雷踏んだわよ あなた
What?!
えっ？
So we have a total of 200m
in communication cables, huh?
持ち合わせの通信ケーブルは２００メートル分か
The furthest they'll go is the
elevator hall on the second floor.
２階のエレベーターホールまで届かせるのが限度だな
Can you bring Kanehara out there?
そこまで金原の野郎を引っ張り出せるかい？
I'll do my best.
やるだけはやってみよう
Uhm... you're just gonna talk to him, right?
その…話をするだけなんですよね
Yeah.
ああ…
こんな所にいたのか！黄緑野郎
So this is where you were, yellow-green!
Does food taste better after killing someone?!
人殺しの後の飯はうまいか？
Well?! Does it?!
ええ どうなんだ
塩山も浅見も郡山も貴様が殺した
Shioyama, Asami, and Koriyama...
You killed them all, didn't you?!
そうだな？
Wh-Why are you saying that?
なっ　何で　そんな…
As long as you confine yourself
in here, we can't prove your crime.
貴様がここに閉じこもってるかぎり 犯罪は立証できない
But, I don't like you!
だがな　俺は貴様が嫌いだ
We, Enforcers, like to push
around other latent criminals.
俺たち執行官はな　他の潜在犯をいたぶるのが好きなんだ
So we'll keep you stuck in this factory
so that you have nowhere to escape to.
だから…貴様がどこにも逃げ出せないよう
この工場に釘付けにしてやる
We're gonna spread
the word on the net right away
早速ネットに言い触らしてやるよ
that Yuji Kanehara is a killer
whose Psycho-Pass is clouded.
金原祐治はサイコパスの濁った人殺しだってな
や…　やめて…
D-Don't!
Oops. This place is out
of service range. Oh well.
おっと　ここは圏外だっけな
仕方ない ちょっと玄関まで行ってくる
I'm just gonna head
out to the entrance for a bit.
You can just sit there on
your hands and knees trembling...
貴様はここにはいつくばって震えながら待ってるがいい
...and wait for your own life to be ruined!
自分の人生がぶち壊しになっちまうのをな！
Wh-What're you doing?!
なっ　何やってんですか！狡噛さん！
Mr. Kogami!
Now we'll know for sure if Kanehara
is someone who can kill people.
これで金原が人を殺せるやつかどうかはっきりする
He doesn't have time
to prepare things in advance.
やつには下準備をしている時間もない
If he wants to kill me right away,
he'll use the same MO he used before.
今すぐ俺を始末するなら
前と同じ手口を使うはずだ
When he does, we can prove his crime.
そこで犯罪が立証できる
Th-That's crazy!
む…　むちゃくちゃです！
If he's innocent, we'll be able to
reach outside without any problem.
やつが無実なら
俺たちはこのまま無事に外までたどりつけるだろう
In that case, it's still a happy ending.
それはそれでハッピーエンドだ
Inspector... which would you bet on?
監視官 あんたどっちに懸ける？
That's...
そんな…
It's you guys' fault.
お前らが悪いんだ…
There's our answer, Inspector.
さいの目が出たぜ監視官
Once you're gone,
my Hue can become clean!
お前らさえいなければ…
僕は奇麗になれるんだよ
Run!
走れ
I won't let you get away.
I'll never let you get away.
逃がさない…
お前ら 絶対に逃がさない！
I'll kill you right here right now!
この場で殺してやる
Dammit!
チクショー！
どうして…
Why... Why did you do such a reckless thing?!
どうしてこんな無謀なことを！
This is about finding the truth
behind people's lives and deaths!
人の生き死ににまつわる真相なんだ
If we want to uncover it,
we naturally have to risk our lives!
それを暴こうと思ったら
こっちも命懸けになるのは当然だ
Better speed it up!
We're not gonna make it!
もっと急いで！手遅れになる！
You don't have to tell me! I know that!
んなこた～分かってるっての！
ここだ…
This is the place.
He's in the act of committing a crime,
so we should request assistance and...
もう現行犯なんだから
応援を要請して…
「鎮圧執行システム　オンライン」
Suppression System, online.
Kogami!
狡噛！
You bastards!
貴様らー！
User authentication,
Enforcer Shinya Kogami.
「ユーザー認証 狡噛慎也執行官」
おらー！
Crime Coefficient is 265.
He is a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数２６５　執行対象です」
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さん！
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Destroy Decomposer.
「執行モード デストロイ·デコンポーザー」
Target will be completely eliminated.
「対象を完全排除します」
「ご注意ください」
Please be careful.
Hey, Ko!
おーい　コウちゃん
As always, the Dominators
kick ass when they get serious.
相変わらずしびれるね
ドミネーターの本気は
He said that he wants to be
a detective rather than a hunting dog.
猟犬でなく刑事でありたいと
But the look in his eyes...
そう言っていた彼のまなざしは…
...was unmistakably...
だが　紛れもなく
...that of a carnivore
who had cornered his prey.
獲物を追い詰める肉食獣のそれだった
Looks like the fairy tale died a moment ago
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
I was born behind black iron bars
Wish for payback for the evil done
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
Before you destroy and get destroyed
Pay karma's price, and let's go together
Monster without a name
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.